Today is the sixth day of Navaratri.
今天是Navratri的第6天
There have been many incarnations of the Goddess
已經有很多為各種
for different, different purposes.
不同目的的女神化身
But when the great saints introspect themselves,
當偉大的聖人們自己內省時
who were worshipping the Mother,
他們禮拜母親（the mother）
they found out that what She has done for us.
他們發現祂為我們所做的事
The other day I told you the dharma
前些日子，我告訴你們，正法(the Dharma)
is the innate valency of human beings. And they are ten.
是人類與生俱來最根本的本質 (valency化合價)，共有10個
This is already established within us, but we deviate,
已經建立在我們的內在。但是我們偏離
deviate from dharma and all the problems come in,
背棄了正法，所有的問題因而產生
because to leave the dharma is not a human quality.
因為脫離正法，不是人類的一個特質
But Goddess Herself has done so many things for us already, within us,
女神本身已經為我們做了許多事情，早已存在我們的內在
though we are not aware of it.
雖然，我們沒有知覺到祂
It is said that “ya Devi sarva bhuteshu” -
例如這句 “Ya Devi Sarva Bhuteshu”
"all those whom You have created", - means mostly the human beings -
即「所有那些祢已創造的」，指的是大部份在人類裡的創造
"What do You do? As what do You exist inside the human beings? ”.
祢化為什麼呢？祢以什麼存在於人類的裡面？
Now, just introspect if you have these qualities within you or not,
現在，只要反省，「自己內在有沒有這些特質？」
because they are given to you by the Goddess, by the Shakti within you.
因為這些特質是女神賜給你的，那是你內在的女神(Shakti)
Like: ”Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu shanti rupena samstitha”.
像: ”Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu shanti rupena samstitha”
is very important, that You exist within the human beings as peace.
這是非常重要的，即祢以平靜存在於人類的內在
Do you find thus human beings who are peaceful within and without?
你有找到過那些內在及外在都平靜的人類嗎？
Very difficult. But She has given you that,
非常困難。但女神已經把它賜給你
She has given you that peace which you have to achieve.
女神已經賜給你平靜了，那是你必須去達到的
Now it comes, because you have fallen off your human dharmas.
現在，所有的問題出現，是因為你的人類正法已經墮落
So this peace that She has given you, you have to achieve
因此，這個女神已經賜給你的平靜
through your ascent, through the Kundalini awakening.
你必須透過你的升進、透過靈量覺醒(Kundalini awakening)來達到
You are excited, all right. Or, you want to take revenge,
你很激動，好吧；或者你想報復
you want to hurt others, you want to trouble others;
你想傷害其他人，你想找別人麻煩
you enjoy sometimes, even as sahaja yogis
你是享受這麼做的。甚至身為霎哈嘉瑜伽士
people enjoy hurting others, troubling others.
人們還是享受傷害他人，找別人麻煩
So, the second one She says is:
所以，第二個女神說的是
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu pritti rupena samsthita”.
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu Vritti rupena samsthita”
Pritti  is the quality of loving,
Vritti，是愛的特質
that a human being has been given the quality of loving.
人類已經被賦予愛的特質
But, it’s not there.
但它不見了
Because first nonsensical thing human beings have is jealousy.
因為人類有的第一個荒謬事是嫉妒
Now, supposing I give some present to somebody,
現在，假設我給某人某樣禮物
and some present to another one.
給另一個人另一樣
Even in Sahaja Yoga they feel jealous. Very surprising.
即使在霎哈嘉瑜伽裡，他們感到嫉妒；非常令人驚訝！
How can you, when the Goddess has given you the quality to love?
你怎麼會呢？當女神已經給了你愛的特質之後？
Very, very common nonsense about it is that human beings are very jealous.
關於這點，非常、非常常見的胡扯是，「人類是非常善妒的」
But as sahaja yogis you should not do,
但身為霎哈嘉瑜伽士，你不應該嫉妒
because that quality that the Goddess has given you is of loving.
因為那個女神已經賜給你的特質是愛
That quality should be shown - on the contrary you are very jealous.
這個特質應該彰顯出來。但相反的，你卻非常嫉妒
That means you are not a sahaja yogi, blessed by Shri Mataji - no.
那意味着，你還不是一個受Shri Mataji祝福的霎哈嘉瑜伽士 - 不
If you are blessed, then you will have no jealousy whatsoever.
如果你是受到祝福的，那麼你無論如何都不會嫉妒
And this jealousy sometimes it goes to this extent that
這個嫉妒，有時會走到這種程度；例如
"Now, we are, say, from Cabella, so you are from Albera. Finished!"
我們來自卡貝拉(Cabella)，而你來自Albera。完了。
These so close to each other.
這二個地方如此的近
Just like the two nostrils together. But there will be jealousy.
就像二個鼻孔在一起；但這樣也會有嫉妒
There will be jealousy about, ”Why not Mother come to my country,
嫉妒「為什麼母親不來我的國家
if You can go to that country”.
如果你可以去那個國家？」
So this comes also from the ignorance that
所以，嫉妒也來自於無知：
“This is mine, this is mine, this is yours”.
「這是我的、這個是我的、這是你的」
This jealousy starts in such a funny manner that we do not realize also
嫉妒開始於這種可笑的態度，同時我們也不明白
that She has given us the power to love. Tremendous power to love.
女神已經給了我們愛的力量、極大的愛的力量
Inauspicious power, our cannot be.
不吉祥的力量，無法成為我們的
But auspicious, dharmic power to love somebody.
而是愛某人的吉祥的正法力量
Means without any lust and greed, without any jealousy.
意思是沒有任何的欲望及貪婪，沒有任何嫉妒
But the human mind has developed itself so cunning
但人類的心思自行發展得如此的狡猾
that it is proud that it can be jealous of someone.
它是可以以嫉妒他人來自豪的。
Out of this jealousy only greed comes in, as I told you.
出於嫉妒，貪婪便跟著來，如同我告訴過你的
Is a fact, because you feel jealous - so you want to buy the same thing.
這是事實，因為你感到嫉妒，所以你想買相同的東西
Then you must compete with others.
那你必須跟其他人競爭
If somebody has got a job better than yours, then you must compete with him.
如果某人得到一個比你更好的工作，那麼，你必須競爭
These things are all destructive and the powers of Goddess are constructive.
這些事情全都是毀滅性的，但女神的力量是建設性的
She gives you all the powers that are absolutely constructive.
祂給你的所有力量，都是絕對建設性的
Then She says, “Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu”, the saints have said it,
聖人們曾經說過，「Ya Devi Sarvabhuteshu
- "kshama rupena samsthita”.
- "kshama rupena samsthita」
Kshama is what you call is the forgiveness.
Kshama 是你所說的原諒
Forgiveness from the heart.
打從心裡原諒
All right, somebody has been cruel to you, has been nasty to you,
好吧，某人曾經殘酷的對待你，對你很惡劣
has exploited you, has troubled you,
剝削你，找你麻煩
but you have the power, greater power to forgive.
但是你擁有力量、極大的力量去原諒
Do we use that power to forgive?
我們有使用這個力量去原諒嗎？
Then for relaxing also, what does She do, that She gives you the sleep.
再者，為了讓你放鬆，女神做了什麼？祂賜給你睡眠
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu nidra rupena samsthita”.
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu nidra rupena samsthita”
When you are tired and you can’t sleep
當你累了，卻睡不著
She makes you sleep. She relaxes you. So the power of relaxation She does
祂使你睡覺，祂讓你放鬆。所以，祂是放鬆的力量
because She acts through parasympathetic nervous system.
因為祂透過副交感神經系統運作
The sympathetic nervous system can excite you, can depress you.
交感神經系統能刺激你，能抑制你
But the parasympathetic relaxes you, relaxes your heart,
但副交感神經系統使你放鬆，緩和你的心臟
relaxes your body and completely feel relaxed
讓你的身體休息，你感到全然地放鬆
and sleeping in the lap of your Mother.
如同睡在自己母親的膝上。有很多人無法入睡
But there are many people who cannot sleep.
有很多人無法入睡
Because they are thinking about something they have to achieve.
因為他們老想著他們必須完成的事情
If you cannot sleep, then something wrong with you.
如果你無法入睡，那麼你有些不妥當
And when you cannot sleep I also cannot sleep.
當你無法入睡，我也不能入睡
Whatever collectively happening also works on Me.
不論集體地發生什麼事，同時也作用在我身上
Anything wrong you do, that works on Me, specially collectively.
你犯的任何錯，也作用在我身上；特別是集體地
So you cannot sleep because you are thinking of things which are of no value.
你無法入睡，因為你正想著沒有價值的事情
Now, to overcome that in Sahaja Yoga
若要克服的話，在霎哈嘉瑜伽裡
we know we have to go into thoughtless awareness.
我們知道我們必須進入無思慮的知覺狀態(thoughtless awareness)
But when your ego is working or...
但是當你的自我（ego）正在運作中….
This child is very disturbing. I've seen him all the time running about.
[這個小孩非常的干擾。我看他不時的跑來跑去
Better tell him. Whose son is he?
最好告訴他。他是誰的兒子？]
You see, in India you’ll find children absolutely keeping quiet.
在印度，你會發現小孩絕對的保持安靜
Why? Because the mother takes up the responsibility to train the child.
為什麼呢？因為，做母親的，擔起訓練小孩的責任
So many programs you have had, have you ever seen
你參加過許多的講座，可曾看過
any child running about? Yesterday also they were running about here.
任何小孩跑來跑去的？昨天，他們也全都在這裡跑跳
The reason is mother doesn’t take responsibility as a mother
原因是：做母親的，沒有擔起身為母親的責任
to see that the children are properly brought up.
去注意小孩是否恰當地被教養
Even you are so old, but I have to tell you.
即使你已經這麼大了，我還是必須告訴你們
Whatever is good for you, for your society, a new generation that has come.
不論什麼，只要對你、對你的社會及已出生的新生代來說是好的事
In this new generation if you still are not behaving in a proper way,
在這個新世代，如果你仍然沒有恰當的行為舉止
in abnormal way, how can you impress others?
那你如何令其他人印象深刻呢？
So, Mother has to tell you.
所以，母親必須告訴你。
The most interesting thing that the Mother has put in you is
母親放在你裡面最有趣的特質是
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu bhranti rupena samsthita”.
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu bhranti rupena samsthita”
She puts you into delusion,
祂把你放入幻相裡
because sometimes the children cannot understand
因為，有時候，孩子們是無法瞭解的
unless and until they face the delusion. They have to face the delusion.
除非他們面對幻相。他們不得不面對幻相
She allows, allows you to go wrong
母親允許的，允許你出錯
to a point where you discover you are lost.
「到一個點」，此時你發現你迷失了
Very important it is that She plays,
這是非常重要的，就是祂會演戲
this is the Mahamaya part as they say.
這就是他們所說的大幻相(Mahamaya摩訶摩耶)
And this is discussed in every religion
在每個宗教都討論到這點
that we get lost with this delusion.
即我們會迷失在幻相裡
Now, what are the delusions we have?
現在，我們有那些幻相呢？
We have the delusions of ego.
我們有自我(ego)的幻相
Ego for men as if they are very powerful,
男人的自我(ego)是他們好像都非常有力量
that they can do what they like and they are not going to be punished for it.
他們可以做他們想做的事，而且不會因此受罰
For women they too behave in the same manner.
至於女人，她們也以相同的心態舉止
They don’t understand that this is a delusion
大家不瞭解，這是母親給我們的幻相
the Mother has given into us for us to find out that we are in the wrong.
好讓我們發現自己正在錯誤裡
Because if you tell somebody, “This is wrong, you don’t do it”,
因為，如果你告訴某人，「這是錯的，你不要做了」
still they are not matured enough so they’ll go on doing wrong things.
可是，他們還不夠成熟，他們繼續做錯誤的事
So the Mother says, “All right, go on. Very nice, very good. Very good thing.
所以，母親說，「繼續，非常好，非常好，非常好的事，」
You’ll jump in the sea? – Jump”.
你想跳進海裡，「跳啊」
Then when you realize that you have been in a delusion,
當你明白了自己是在幻相裡
then only you can return back.
那麼你才會走回來
Otherwise without any problem you cannot return.
否則，沒遇到任何問題，你不會走回來
So many of you are so obstinate, so self-conscious.
你們許多人是如此的固執、如此的自我意識
Whatever one may tell you, you will not listen.
不論人們告訴你什麼，你都不會聽
Whatever way you may try to convince, on a mental level, you won’t.
在思想層面，不論我們用什麼方法嘗試使你相信，你都不信
So, the bhranti, the delusion, is beyond the mind.
所以，bhranti，即幻相，是超越心智的
It is beyond the mind.
祂是超越心智的
It works out sometimes very well for difficult people.
對頑強的人而言，有時候，祂運作得非常好
Now, when you are in a position of a Mother
現在，當你是在母親的位置
you don’t want Your child to be ruined, naturally.
自然地，你不想你的小孩變壞
She feels responsible, and She thinks that:
母親感到有責任，而且祂想
“Now they have got connection with the Divine,
現在孩子們已經跟上天取得連結
and this connection should not be broken,
這個連結不該打斷
that they should be all the time blessed and be happy.
孩子們應該永遠受到祝福而且快樂
All this is within us,
所有這些特質都在我們內在
within us, built-in, from our very childhood,
從我們幼年期就已建立在我們裡面
but we forget, slowly, slowly we start losing it.
但是我們忘記了。一點點的，慢慢地，我們開始失去祂
Maybe the conditioning is such or maybe the ego is such,
也許制約是這樣的，也許自我是這樣的
and maybe that they forget that they are realized souls.
也可能他們忘了自己是已自覺的靈
I’m talking to you - to people who are realized souls. I’m not talking
我正在跟你說話，跟「已得自覺的靈」說話；我不是在跟
to people who are already lost or who may be on their way to Sahaja Yoga.
已經迷失了的人，或才剛往霎哈嘉瑜伽而來的人說話
But the way you are brought up, the way you have been told
你是用非常和譪、用愛、用眷顧
very sweetly with love, with affection, with kindness,
及用仁慈來養育及教導的
and if you don’t understand that, then you go into bhranti.
如果你不明白這點，那麼，你走入幻相(bhranti)裡
For example, it is also said that,
例如，還有
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu lajja rupena samsthita”.
“Ya Devi sarva bhuteshu lajja rupena samsthita”
Lajja, I don’t know how to describe, it’s not shyness.
Lajja，我不知道如何描述，它不是羞怯
It is a kind of a shame about your body.
它是對自己身體的一種羞恥心
Now they have beauty contests. India also they had beauty contest.
現在，人們舉辦選美活動，在印度也是，他們舉辦選美活動
Why are you writing? What is he writing?
為什麼你在寫字？在寫什麼？
There’s no need to write, there will be a tape. Alright?
不需要記下來，將來會有影帶，好嗎？
Lajja rupena samsthita:
Lajja rupena samsthita:
means you have to have shame of your body.
意思是，對自己的身體要有羞恥心
That’s specially for women.
特別是女人
As a child you will see, women are very shy.
還是小孩子時，你看到，女人是非常害羞的
See, little girls, they are
看看小女孩，她們是非常害羞的
That shyness gradually disappears,
漸漸地，害羞不見了
but in the beginning they are even shy of Me.
但在剛開始時，她們甚至對我感到害羞
They come before Me, they’ll put down their head.
她們來到我面前，會低著頭
They’ll not even say Namaste. Very sweet.
甚至不會說Namaste(“敬禮”之意)，非常甜美
And they don’t like people wearing funny dresses.
而且她們不喜歡人們穿可笑的衣服
I remember My granddaughter once, she saw one magazine
我記得我的孫女，有一次她看見一本雜誌
in which there was a lady in a swimming dress. She said, “What are you doing?
上面有位穿泳裝的女士。她說，「你在做什麼？
Better wear your dress, otherwise my Grandma will come and hit you hard”.
最好穿上你的衣服；不然，我奶奶來了，會重重打你」
To that lady was saying that; and then she opened and saw a man’s dress
她對雜誌上的那位女士這樣說。後來，她打開雜誌，看見一位男士穿著
with just a small, little knicker. I don’t know why they do it.
一條小短褲 -我不知道他們為什麼這樣做
And then she said, “This one is, seems to be absolutely shameless fellow.
接著，她說，「這個人似乎是絕對無恥的人
He is going to have a bad time now.” And she closed it.
現在，他將要倒大楣了，」然後，她合上雜誌
And then she told the maidservant, “Burn this, burn this off.
告訴女僕，「燒了這個，燒掉這本雜誌
I don’t want to see.” Such a little girl she knew that it was wrong.
我不想看了。」這樣的小女孩，她知道這樣是錯的
But the way nowadays we are going about with the show of our body,
但現今，我們卻開始賣弄我們的身體
and sometimes I feel that all these designers will die
有時侯，我覺得所有的設計師會死亡
or will get bankrupt, because people wear such little clothes these days.
或破產，因為如今人們穿得這麼少
There is no space for any artist
沒有餘地讓藝術家展現他的工作
to show his work or to show his art how he can dress you up.
或展示他的藝術作品，讓他好好的為你打扮
In Japan I asked them how - this is long time back, now Japanese are Americans
在日本，我問他們「為什麼……」這是好久以前了，現在日本就像美國
but at that time - I said, “How is it you wear these dresses, these kimonos,
但在那時候—-我問，「為什麼你們穿這些衣服，這和服(kimonos)
done so well, very expensive and it takes time to wear that?”.
縫製得如此好，非常昂貴，而且需要花費時間去穿著？
So they said that, “You see, if God has made a beautiful body,
他們說，「您看，如果神創造出如此美麗的身體
then it is His art,
那是神的藝術
and we have to make our art decorate it.
而我們必須用我們的藝術去裝飾它
So what we do is to make our art to decorate it.”
我們所做的是用我們的藝術去裝點它
I really liked it, because in India same thing.
我真的喜歡它。因為在印度，也是這樣的
If there is a lady she has to wear a sari,
如果有位女士必須穿一件紗麗
which is being made very artfully, very beautifully,
紗麗被製造得非常精巧、非常美麗
just to decorate her body, just to respect the body.
只為了點綴她的身體，只為了尊敬身體
But this seems to have gone with the influence of America,
但這點似乎受美國的影響而消失了
I should say, which are, they are brainless people, absolutely brainless,
我應該說。他們是沒頭腦的人，絕對的愚笨
nothing to learn from them. Only two-hundred-year-old people
從他們身上沒什麼好學的。只有200年歷史的人
and we start behaving in their manner,
我們卻開始跟隨他們的舉止行為
we don’t see even what is happening to their country,
我們甚至沒看見他們的國家發生了什麼事？
what sort of people they are, how they live, what is their idea,
他們是怎樣的人？他們怎樣生活？他們的想法是什麼？
what is their goal in life. Every false guru has exploited them,
他們的生命目標是什麼？每一個假導師都剝削他們
because they are brainless. If they had brains
因為他們沒頭腦；如果他們有頭腦
they would never have accepted them.
就絕不會接受這些
Ha, they have brains how to run a computer
他們有腦筋去使用電腦
and how to run a television - mechanical things.
或操作電視、機械等
But as far as their own body is concerned, they don’t know how to manage.
但就他們自己的身體而言，他們不知道如何管理
In India they had a beauty competition and many sensible people opposed it,
在印度，人們舉辦選美比賽，許多明理人反對它
because it’s like selling your body and making money.
因為它像在出售你的身體賺錢
What is the difference between prostitution and this?
選美跟賣淫，這二者有什麼差別？
If you get money by selling your body, then it’s prostitution.
如果你出售你的身體而賺錢，那麼，那就是賣淫
You are not supposed to sell your body.
你不應該出售你的身體
That’s not what Goddess has done to you.
那不是女神為你做的
But you should dress up well, different, different occasions are there,
你應該裝扮合宜，有各種不同的場合存在
for those occasions you have to wear the way it is.
你必須依那些場合穿著
The other day I gave a very nice sari which is,
前幾天，我送了一件非常好的紗麗
we call as paithani to one lady as a present.
我們稱它為「paithani」給一位女士，當做禮物
And we had a function for a book, was inaugurated,
我們有個新書的發表會
and this lady came there. So I said, “Why didn’t you wear a paithani?”
這位女士也到來。我說，「為什麼你沒穿你的『paithani』？」
She said, “What, there is no wedding on.
她說，「什麼！這又不是婚禮
How can I wear for this function paithani? There has to be a wedding.”
這場合我怎麼能穿『paithani』，必須是婚禮才行
Very sweet – “in the wedding I can wear.”
很甜美，「我在婚禮上我會穿。」
It is all, you see occasions, places which are to be celebrated.
有各式各樣的節慶場合及地點
Like in India, when women go to the temple
例如，在印度，當婦女去廟裡
or to worship the idols or anything,
或去禮拜神像，或做任何事
then they will wear all that is necessary to face the Goddess, after all.
那麼他們會穿上一切必要的，畢竟是去面對女神
Imagine people coming for this program here wearing,
想像一下，人們為這個活動來到這裡，卻穿著
I don’t know what they call it, but like jute, jute clothes - like hippies,
我不知道他們怎麼稱呼它，像黃麻、黃麻布-像個嬉皮士
what would happen to Me? I would disappear in thin air, I can tell you this much.
我會發生什麼事呢？我會消失得無影無縱，我暫且告訴你這些而已
So, one has to have respect for the body.
所以，我們必須尊敬身體
That is what She has said first - that “Lajja rupena samsthita”.
這是祂說的第一個「Lajja rupena samsthitah(對自己的身體有羞恥心)。」
Now you might say that there are people who are taking the bath in the river
你可能會說，「有些人在河裡洗澡
and this and that, and give justification.
還有這個、那個….，」找理由辯解
But you are saints! You are realized souls!
但是，你們是聖人，你們是已得自覺的靈
You don’t have to see those people who are not yet realized
你們不必去看那些還沒得到自覺的
and who are misbehaving.
以及行為不端的人
You must do what a saint should do.
你們必須做聖人應該做的事
There are so many qualities that the Goddess has given you.
女神已經給了你這麼多的特質
Another is kshudha rupena samstitha.
另一個是「Kshuddha rupena samsthitah」
She’s the One who has given us hunger. We have to eat our food.
祂是給我們饑餓的那一位，我們必須吃東西
Nowadays there’s a fashion of becoming thin or whatever you may call.
現今，有個要變瘦的潮流，或隨你怎麼稱呼它
And you know so many diseases have developed.
你知道已經有許多的疾病
Anorexia, this thing, that thing, because women want to eat little.
像：厭食、這樣的事、那樣的事，因為女人想吃少一點
You can change the things that you are eating,
你可以改變你吃的東西
but it’s not the aim of life to only look after your body.
但是只照顧自己的身體(身材)，並不是生命的目標
Body is not the only important thing. What is important is your Spirit.
身體不是唯一重要的事情，重要的是你的靈 (Spirit)
And She is the One who gives you the Kundalini.
祂是給你靈量(kundalini)的那位
She is the One who give you a method by which you’ll ascend.
祂是給你一個方法讓你得以升進的那位
But all the time worried about their body.
但是人們卻老在擔心自己的身體
This is something I can’t understand. Specially the women who are the shakti.
這是我無法瞭解的事；尤其是女人，她們是力量(shakti)
Then another point is that they follow a fashion.
另一點是，人們跟隨潮流
Fashion is madness.
潮流是瘋狂的
When I was young I used to wear My blouses like this only.
當我年輕時，我習慣穿的上衣，袖長只像這樣(接近手肘)
But in India also fashion started.
但是，在印度，也開始有了潮流
They used to increase the size of the sleeves,
他們曾經加長袖子的長度
then decreased the size of the sleeves, then some went up to here.
後來，縮短袖子的長度；然後，有一些短到這裡(無袖)
I thought, “What is this nonsense? Why waste money like this?”.
我想這是什麼樣的胡鬧？為什麼這樣浪費錢？
You have a particular design,
你有個既定的設計
and this is traditionally accepted design, that you should have.
而且是傳統流傳下來大家接受的，你應該接受
Why do you want to go on increasing and decreasing
為什麼你要不斷照著潮流，加長和縮短
the size of your sleeves, according to the fashion. “This is the fashion”.
袖子的長度呢？「這是潮流。」
Who makes the fashion? Devi? Devi has made the fashion?
誰創造這個潮流？女神嗎？女神創造的潮流嗎？
Who has made the fashion? Is these hungry, greedy people
誰創造這個潮流的？是饑餓、貪心的人
who are befooling you. And you are trying to follow fashions.
他們愚弄你，而你卻試圖跟隨潮流
Now, for example, I told that you must put oil in your head,
例如，我告訴過你，你必須在你頭上放些油，
at least on Saturday put sufficient oil and then wash your head.
至少星期六，放充分的油；然後再洗頭
But you’ll not do that and then you’ll start losing your hair.
但是，你不做；然後，你開始掉髮
I can understand if you have no time, you are a very busy man - but why?
我能瞭解，如果你沒時間，你是很忙的人，但是為什麼？
Why not do something where it is needed to look after yourself also.
為什麼不做些需要照顧自己的事？
So, you’ll look after your body to thin down, you’ll lose your hair,
你照料你的身體為了要瘦下來，你失去你的頭髮
eyesight will be weak, your teeth will be falling,
視力也變弱、牙齒也開始掉下來
and you will become very soon an old hag.
很快的，你變成一個老太婆
Same with the men, nowadays men are also going to beauty parlor, I’m told.
男人也一樣。現今，男人也去美容院，有人告訴我的
Too much money I think, and stupidity together.
錢太多了，我想；再加上愚蠢
There is no need. If you lead a good, healthy life
沒有需要啊！如果你要過一個美好的、健康的生活
- you have to exercise and meditate.
你必須運動及靜坐
If you meditate you become peaceful.
如果你有靜坐，你變得平靜
With that peace, you’ll be amazed, you’ll have so much of energy.
以那個平靜，你會驚訝於你擁有這麼多的精力
So much energy is wasted in thinking. And what do you think?
如此多的精力被浪費在「思想」上面，那你在想什麼呢？
If you ask somebody: “What are you thinking?”
如果你問某人，「你在想什麼呢？」
“Everything.” But “everything” means what?
回答說，「每件事。」但，想每件事，即是什麼意思呢？
Why do you think so much? What is the need to think?
為什麼你想這麼多？有什麼需求，要去想？
It’s a habit, human habit to go on thinking about everything.
這是一個習慣、人類的習慣，不斷的想每件事
For example, just now, there are three carpets here.
例如，此刻，這裡有三張地毯
Now, if I put attention on it I’ll just see how nice they are; I’ll just enjoy
如果我把注意力放在它上面，我只會看見這些地毯多麼美
- enjoy what the artists have done, that’s all.
我只是享受，享受藝術家的作為；就這樣而已
No words - nothing. Just the enjoyment within yourself.
沒有言論，什麼話也沒有，只有自己內在的享受而已
But if you ask somebody else, he’ll just start saying,
但如果你問其他人，他會開始說
“Oh, this is not good. That’s not good.
「哦，這個不好、那個不好
This much some price, that price, this thing, that thing.”
這個價錢太高，這樣，那樣」
The joy of that artist is finished.
那個藝術家的喜悅結束掉了
You cannot get that joy,
你無法得到那個喜悅
that joy about which we are seeking. What we are seeking is joy,
那個我們正在尋找的喜悅，我們正在找尋的是喜悅
and even when you have got a way of doing it you do not achieve it.
即使你已經獲得做這事的方法，你也無法達到它
Because thinking is a reaction, reaction to everything,
因為「思想」，就是起反應、對每件事起反應
and it makes the life so miserable.
這使得生命如此的悲慘
It makes the life of the person who thinks and of others also.
使「思想」的這個人的，還有其他人的生命都這樣
I’ll give you an example. This whole thing we got it done
我給你舉個例子，這整件事，我們會做這件事
just because it’s very heavy rains and also we have
只因為，會下非常大的雨，而且有時侯
problems of sometimes snowing.
我們也有下雪的問題
So I thought that’s a nice thing to have a nice thing done
因此，我想去做一件體貼的事就是件體貼的事，
and it’s very well done, we got it.
而且做得非常好，我們做到了
Now, there are thinking people in this Italy. Lots of them.
現在，在義大利有很會「思想」的人、有很多
That’s why it’s not progressing. Now, we applied three years back.
這就是為什麼不會進步。我們3年前申請的
Three years they kept our money locked up in the bank, imagine.
他們把我們的錢，鎖在銀行3年，想像一下吧
And first time they said, “All right, everything is fine, it’s all right.
第一次，他們說，「好，一切都很好，這很好
You can have it.” It had seventy signatures
你可以拿到它；」它上面有這些所謂的
of these Italians, so-called.
義大利人的70個簽名
And then they came round to say, the same people,
然後，他們來訪，並且說 — 同一批人哦
“No, no, no, you must change it to copper”. I said, “Why?”
「不，不，不，你必須把它改成銅制的，」我說，「為什麼？」
“Because copper will be aesthetically very good.”
回答說，「因為銅有美感、非常好。」
But don’t they know, stupid people, that copper will look the same
但是他們不知道嗎？愚蠢的人，銅看起來會
as they are looking? After one month only they will have the same colour?
跟它們看起來一樣；一個月以後，它們就會有同樣的顏色嗎？
This is the idea of aesthetics, and now I have told them,
這就是美學的觀念。現在，我已經告訴他們了
“We don’t want your land, you keep it to yourself, give us back our money.”
「我們不要你的土地，你們自己留著吧，把錢還給我們。」
With a simple thing like that.
像這麼簡單的一件事！
Why? Because they have a committee, there is “rejune, bijune, sijune”.
為什麼會這樣呢？因為他們有個委員會，有Rejuvne, bejvne, sejuvne
You have to go through all that nonsense,
我們不得不歷經所有的胡扯
because they all sit down on chairs, very seriously,
因為他們全部都非常嚴肅的坐在椅子上
“We must discuss, we must consult, we must ask everyone,
「我們必須討論、我們必須協商、我們必須問每一個人」
and then this and that”. And ultimately what comes?
然後，還有這個、那個。最後，結果是怎樣？
No progress of any kind. There is no peace.
沒有任何進步，沒有平靜
Maybe, I don’t know, maybe some underhand dealings are needed,
可能，我不知道，可能需要一些私底下的交易
for which they are feeling shy to tell Me. I don’t know what is the thing is,
但他們又覺得不好意思告訴我們； 我不知道是什麼事
but still I can’t understand when the one office says “Yes”
但我還是不瞭解，當辦事處原先說，「好；」
and again, when it comes back to it, it says “No”. Three years.
但再去一次，又說，「不好；」3年了！
So, what I am trying to say that thinking too much is a sign of ego.
我要說的是：想得太多，是自我(ego)的徵兆。
But, they don’t find any solutions, no solutions of any kind.
他們找不到任何的解決方法、沒有任何解決方法
They’ll never hit the solution. Because they are just discussing,
他們絕對無法找到解決之道，因為他們只是不斷討論著
arguing, thinking - they have no solutions.
爭辯著、想著，他們沒有解決的辦法
Now, it is important that sahaja yogis have to do introspection,
如今，很重要的是，霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須反省
introspection - inward. Introspection is inward-looking.
向內的反省。反省是向內看的。向內看
Inward-looking. “Why I am thinking? What am I thinking?
「為什麼我在想？我在想什麼？
What is the need to think?”.
有什麼需要去想呢？」
You will become Nirvichara. Don’t allow your mind to befool you.
你將成為Nirvichar(無思慮的入靜狀態)。不要允許你的心智愚弄你
This mind is like a monkey, I tell you, it’s really like a monkey.
這個心智就像一隻猴子，我告訴你，它真的像隻猴子
And when it starts working it makes you jump from this end to that end,
當它開始運作，它讓你從這端跳到那端
that end to that end. And if you reach some conclusions, so-called,
從那端再跳到另一端。如果你得到某個所謂的結論
and if it is not achieved then you are the most miserable person.
之後卻又沒有達成它，那麼你就是最悲慘的人
I have seen people thinning down only thinking about something which is absurd.
我曾看過人們瘦下來，卻只想著一些荒謬的事
And you can see out of this thinking what comes out
你可以看見這個「想」衍生出什麼
on a global level also. What is the need to go to the moon?
在全世界的層面也是一樣，有什麼需要去月球呢？
So many people are starved, are dying out.
那麼多人挨餓，快要死了！
What is the need to go to Mars?
有什麼需要去火星呢？
What are they going to get from there? Because they formed a habit.
他們想從那裡得到什麼呢？因為人們已經養成一個習慣
First they came to India, then went to China,
首先他們來到印度、然後再去中國
then went to this, then went to that; they can’t sit down, settle down.
再來去這裡、再去那裡。他們不能坐下來、安定下來
They can’t settle down in the house also.
他們也不能在自己的家裡安定下來
Specially men. If you are travelling by train,
尤其是男人。如果你搭火車旅行
even if the train stops for two minutes men must get out.
即使火車停下來２分鐘，男人也必須出去
The wife will be worried now. And while the train will be moving
妻子則開始擔心。當火車要開動了
then they’ll jump in.
他們才會跳上來
It’s a cracked brain, I think, like a - even why say they are like a monkey?
這是瘋子的腦袋，我想，甚至，為什麼說像一隻猴子呢？
Because monkeys won’t do that.
因為猴子也不會那樣做
It’s that they cannot stationary remain in one place.
他們就是無法保持不動的待在一個地方
Now, in meditation you have to sit down, in one place,
靜坐時，你必須在一個地方坐下來
not to jump from here to there, there to there. This is very difficult.
而不是從這裡跳到那裡、那裡跳到這裡，那樣會非常困難的
Women have other problems. While cooking they’ll meditate.
女人有另外的問題，正在煮飯時，她們會靜坐
They have no time!
她們沒有時間
They have their friends, they have to go to shopping,
她們有自己的朋友，她們必須去購物
to buy things and fill the house with all kinds of rubbish.
買東西，用各式各樣的垃圾填滿房子
They have no time for anything. They are also very adventurous.
她們對任何事都沒時間。她們也非常大膽
They want to do business, they want to do this, they want to do that.
她們想去做生意；她們想做這個，想做那個
For meditation they have no time.
靜坐呢，她們沒有時間！
So, settling down is very important. Settle down with yourself.
所以，安定下來是非常重要的，把自己安定下來吧
So, once someone told Me, “Mother, if we settle down, we’ll become very fat.”
有人告訴我，「母親，如果我們安定下來，我們會變得非常胖」
All right, doesn’t matter - but you settle down.
好吧，沒有關係，只要你安定下來
All sorts of excuses are there not to meditate.
各種不靜坐的藉口都有
“Yes, I meditate, Mother, but you know, so difficult in these modern times.
「是的，我有靜坐；但，母親，您是知道的，在現世代這是如此困難
There are crises in our lives, there are problems in our lives.”
我的生活裡有很多危機，我們生活裡有很多難題。」
But actually you’ll be amazed, when there’s a crisis, say, in My family
但實際上，你會很訝異的，例如，每當我的家裡
or in Sahaja Yoga, immediately I become thoughtless.
或霎哈嘉瑜伽裡有危機時，我立刻變成無思無慮(thoughtless)
Spontaneously I become thoughtless,
自然地我變得無思慮
because the problem will be solved by the Paramchaitanya.
因為問題會被無所不在的生命能量(Parama Chaitanaya)解決掉
The Paramchaitanya is going to solve the problem, why should I think?
無所不在的生命能量會把問題解決掉，為什麼我要想呢？
Forget it. Let the Paramchaitanya look after.
忘掉它吧，讓無所不在的生命能量看顧
If you don’t depend on your Paramchaitanya,
如果你不依靠你的無所不在的生命能量
it doesn’t help you. Doesn’t give you any solutions.
那祂不會幫助你，不會給你任何的解決方法
Then you go on round and round and round with your brain and work it out.
你只能不斷的靠自己的腦筋轉來轉去，設法解決
This is what you have to know definitely that you are connected
這是你必須明確知道的，就是：「你是連結到
to the all-pervading Power of Divine love.
無所不在、神聖的浩愛力量」
This is not love which is stupid - love that thinks.
這個愛，不是愚昧的，祂是會思考的愛
Love that is truth. Love that is joy.
是真理的愛、是喜悅的愛
All this is built in within you, and now you have got realization,
這一切都已建立在你的內在。現在，你已經得到自覺了
so instead of evolving yourself, you just jump into things which are of no value.
却不進化自己，反而跳入沒有價值的事情裡
And so many Sahaja Yogis get lost. I was recently told by someone
這麼多的霎哈嘉瑜伽士迷失了。最近，某人告訴我
that we have lost about hundred sahaja yogis,
我們損失了大約百名霎哈嘉瑜伽士
because they started following another sahaja yogi, who started seeing things.
因為，他們開始跟隨另一位霎哈嘉瑜伽士，他開始看見一些東西
So they also wanted to see.
所以，他們也想要看見
If you can see something that means you are not there, simple thing.
如果你能看見一些什麼，那表示你不在那裡(那境界)；簡單的道理
If I am, say, on the top of a mountain, then I’m there.
如果我……例如，我在山頂上；那麼，我就在那裡
But if I am away from the mountain I can see it.
但如果我遠離那座山，那麼我就能看到它
The more you see something that means you are away from it.
你越能看見某個東西，代表你是遠離那個東西的
Did you follow this point?
你聽得懂這一點嗎？
So, the subtle, the sukshma, state is that
所以，這個精微的、這個Sukshma狀態就是指：
where you are yourself that.
你在那裡，你自己就是那個。
So, how can you see yourself?
那麼，你如何能看見你自己呢？
This is the point Sahaja Yogis must understand. Anybody who can –
就是這一點，霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須瞭解。任何人能的話，說
“Mother, oh no he can see, he saw auras around You,
「母親，哦，不，他能看見！他看見您周圍的氣場(auras)
he can see this thing.” So, how can you see?
他能看見這種事。」那麼，你是如何能看見的？
Because you are that, you can’t see. So, all such people
因為你就是那個，你就無法看見。所有這樣的人
who are very popular sometimes, in the beginning of Sahaja Yoga
在剛開始霎哈嘉瑜伽時，有時侯是非常受歡迎的
try to control you and befool you. And then you are thrown out.
他們試圖去控制你、愚弄你；緊接著，你就被丟出去。
Now, this is what we call is the judgement.
這就是你所稱的「審判時期(the judgement)」
There are sieves and sieves and sieves through which you have to pass.
有許多篩子、無數的篩子，你必須通過這無數的篩子
Where you get enamoured by this or that, or you fall for this or that,
此同時，你被這個或那個迷住，或你因為這個或那個而掉落
all these things are there in a step- by-step how you are arriving.
這一切事情存在著；一步步的，就是你如何到達的。
You are arriving at that point where your destruction is sure.
到達那個你的毀滅的確定的點。
Because you have to become the Spirit. You have to rise in spiritual life.
因為你必須成為靈體 (the spirit)，你不得不在靈性生活上成長
And if your movement is downward, who can help you?
而如果你的移動是向下的，那誰能幫助你呢？
This is a very interesting time as I told you, is the time of judgement.
這是一個非常有趣的時期，如我所告訴你們的，是審判的時刻
And at this time we have to be careful that we are our own judges.
在這個時期，我們不得不小心，因為我們是我們自己的判官
Nobody has to tell you that you are catching this one and catching that one.
沒有人會告訴你，你感染了這個、感染了那個
You yourself can feel it what chakras you are catching.
你，你自己可以感覺到，你什麼輪環感染了
Whatever I may try on My own
憑我一己之力，無論我嘗試什麼方法
to suck in all your problems, do whatever is possible,
吸取你所有的問題；做盡一切能做的事
to keep you rising and rising and rising, but what I feel
保持你上升、上升再上升；但我覺得
that this method of helping you will not make you so strong,
這種幫助你的方式，無法使你變得多麼強壯
because you’ll always think that, “After all, Mother will suck my problem.”
因為你總是想，「終究母親會吸收我的問題
If I get hundred letters, out of them ninety-nine are of sahaja yogis
如果我收到100封信，其中99封來自受苦於
who are suffering from this trouble or that trouble. I’m amazed,
這個問題或那個問題的霎哈嘉瑜伽士；我很驚訝！
you have all these qualities already awakened in you, they are in you.
在你裡面，你已經擁有全部這些早已經覺醒了的特質，祂們在你裡面
You use them.
你要使用這些特質
Somebody will say, “That fellow is troubling me,
有人說，「那個人在找我麻煩
that wife is troubling me, the husband troubling me.” Just forgive!
妻子在找我麻煩、丈夫找我麻煩」就原諒吧！
Just forgive! Your power of forgiveness is poor.
就原諒吧！你原諒的能力太差了
Moreover, more than what the saints have written
此外，比聖人們記載的更多
you have got the power of truth. You know the reality.
你已經得到真理的力量，你知道實相(the reality)
Much more than those saints who have praised the Goddess.
比那些讚美女神的聖人們知道得多。
If you could just think as to what level you are sitting
如果你能想想現在你所處的層次
you wouldn’t fall, you wouldn’t go down that much.
那你就不會掉下來的、你不會向下掉那麼多
Only problem is you have to know that your ascent has to be spiritual,
唯一的問題是你必須知道，你的升進必須是靈性上的
and already these qualities are very well balanced and put within you.
而且這些特質，早已經非常恰當平衡的放在你裡面
More than dharma. Dharma maybe, you have a power
比正法還多；也許正法你有能力去
to give up or to fall down, but these powers are never destroyed within you.
放棄或是墮落，但這些力量在你內在，絕不會被摧毀
I remember once I went to America first time and I met one gentleman.
我記得有一次，我第一次去美國，我遇到一位紳士
The next day he came and he told Me, “Mother, I am changed,
隔天他來，並且告訴我，「母親，我改變了
I am changed, I am changed.” “What happened?”
我改變了，我改變了。」出了什麼事？
“You know, I used to hate my uncle, I never wanted to talk to him,
「我一直恨我的叔叔，從不想跟他說話
very angry with him, but this time, just imagine,
非常生他的氣。但這一次，想像一下
yesterday I met him, I went and hugged him, and kissed him, and I said,
昨天我遇到他。我走過去抱緊他、親他。然後，我說
‘Now, I have forgiven you, completely forgiven you,
『現在，我已經原諒你了，完全原諒你
now don’t think about feeling guilty about it.
現在，不要再想起、不要有罪惡感。』
He started looking at me like this.’”
他開始像這樣看著我。」
So, with the Kundalini awakening
所以，因為靈量(kundalini)的覺醒
all these beautiful qualities you have will come up.
所有這些你擁有的美麗特質將會浮現
And then your generosity,
然後，你那受靈體啟發過的慷慨
your beautiful being, which is enlightened by the Spirit
大方及美麗的本質
will prove to the world that Sahaja Yoga is the truth.
將向這個世界證明霎哈嘉瑜伽是真理。
Yesterday’s beautiful dramas have shown us,
昨天的美好戲劇，已經顯現給我們看了
but it should not be a mental satisfaction within you,
但這不該是你內在思維上的滿足
that “I have got the realization, now I am this”.
「我已經得到自覺了！我就是這個」
No. No. No mental. It’s a state, it’s a state,
不！不！不是思維上的，它是一種狀態。它是一種狀態
and that state to achieve, you have to really meditate
而要達到這種狀態，你必須實在的靜坐
and find time for meditation every night, every morning.
找時間靜坐，每天晚上、每天早上
The more you’ll meditate the better it will be.
你越靜坐，它越好
No excuses are to be given or to be convincing to yourself.
沒有任何藉口或是需要去說服自己
Everything is unimportant. Your ascent is very important,
每件事都不重要，你的升進是非常重要的
if you really want to save this world from - in this Kali Yuga.
如果你真的想從這個鬥爭期(kali yuga)中拯救這個世界
I think today I have made it very clear to you
我想今天，我已經對你說得很清楚了
what qualities already are instilled within you.
你內在早已安置好了什麼特質
They are there. They are not dharmas, but qualities.
它們在那兒，它們不是正法，而是特質(qualities)
They are just within you,
它們就在你內裡。
only thing you have turned your attention to something opposite,
除非你把注意力轉移到事情的對立面
otherwise all these qualities are already instilled within you.
不然全部這些特質早已經安置在你內在了
They are already there. And nothing can destroy them, except for you yourself.
它們早已經在那兒了，而且沒有什麼能毀滅它們，除了你、你本身以外
If you have destroyed them, nobody can help.
如果你已經毀壞它們了，那沒人能幫上忙
May God bless you all.
願神祝福你們所有人！